Luke Belinc

As a software engineer and full stack web developer, I am experienced in contributing to team success through the art of software development and dedication to my craft. Rooted in a passion for learning, I have built a strong skill set which includes 5+ years' experience in applying object-oriented and functional programming techniques.

2 (734) 969-5442

in/in/luke-belinc

₼/luke-belinc

@belinc@tuta.io

Experience

Associate Software Engineer

Verint Systems 02/2022-08/2022

Designed new and maintined existing interal software tools
Automated workflows to create efficiency of scale
Provided continuous QoL updates to legacy software/systems
Built and deployed single page web applications via AWS EC2
Provided necessary CLI training to my team
Coordinated multiple projects from initial planning through deployment
Implemented Agile style software development
Doubled annual 2022 release targets by August 2022

Systems Programmer

WSU-Huang Lab 03/2020-10/2020

Built software extensions for the GEOS-Chem and WRF-Chem modeling systems Wrote scripts to interpret and generate maps from atmospheric data models Automated software execution using Bash, cron, and Slurm via WSU's HPC Implemented GNU Make to automate software builds Provided CLI training to 3 team members

Skill Set

Languages C, C++, C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go, Bash, Haskell, CommonLisp, FORTRAN, Ruby

Frameworks/Libraries Angular, React, Express, Jasmine, POSIX, pandas, Tkinter, NumPy, NLTK, Qt, .NET, ASP.NET, jQuery, Rails

Tools Unix shells (zsh, sh, Bash), GNU coreutils, Vim, Slurm, cron, PowerShell, Git, Node.js, LAT_EX, AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda), Database Managament Systems (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle Database), Jira, Confluence

Methodologies Agile, CI/CD, Behavior- and Test-driven development

Projects/Hackathons

Advent of Code Various code challanges completed using Haskell, C++, and Python

DHack Designed health monitoring app using AWS Lambda, JavaScript and React Native. Won 2nd place overall and 1st place for the FitBit challenge.

MHacks 8 Designed set of dev tools for remote maintainance of GM Console software. Used C, JavaScript, and Wayland to manipulate system and interact with screen remotely.

Chinese Character Dictionary Designed a simple character meaning and stroke order dictionary and thesaurus using Python, PostgreSQL, and Qt

Mock Terminal POSIX shell built in C

Education

Wayne State University
B.S. in Computer Science
Detroit, MI 2016-2021

References

Matthew Crawford
Director, Product Support
(248)595-5635
inLinkedIn

Matthew Heinrich Engineer, DevOps (646)385-5524 inLinkedIn